Arthur W. Leighton Papers MS056
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Arthur W. Leighton Papers
1913 -- 1973
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Leighton, Arthur Whiting
MS056
1.2 Linear Feet
Arrangement
This collection is organized into one series.
Custodial History
For this collection, we combined material sent to the Archives and material from Leighton's vertical file compiled by Russell Miller, which was labeled 'Arthur W. Leighton-biographical.'
Scope and Contents
This collection includes church organizational documents and brochures, correspondence, educational records, essays, news clippings and photographs from Tufts University professor Arthur Whiting Leighton. In addition to his service to Tufts as a professor of engineering design and graphics, Leighton was active in a number of local Congregational church organzations. Some of these organizations included in his papers are North Street Church, Boston Congregational Club, Woburn Association of Congregational Christian churches and United Church of Christ.
Biographical / Historical
Arthur Whiting Leighton (March 7, 1894 - March 12, 1973) served as instructor of technical design at the University of Maine (1914-1917), as instructor of technical drawing at Tufts (1917-1919) where he also took classes and was made an honorary member of the class of 1917, and as a mathematics teacher at the Huntington School (1921-1922). He received his B.S. from the University of Massachusetts in 1921, his Ed. M. from Harvard in 1924, and his Ed. D. from Harvard in 1932.
As professor of engineering graphics Leighton taught engineering design at Tufts for over 45 years (1917-1963) and was known for his dedication to students. Leighton served as counselor for freshman and sophomore engineering students from 1931-1960 and as director of counseling for the College of Liberal Arts and Jackson College from 1936-1948. From 1944-1946, he served as director of the Veteran's Center at the Tufts School for War Veterans. During his life, Leighton was active in various Congregational church organizations. He was married to Frances Rowland Freeman, and they had one son, Arthur W. Leighton, Jr.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Leighton, Arthur Whiting; North Street Church; Boston Congregational Club; Woburn Association of Congregational Christian churches; United Church of Christ; Faculty papers; University history; Tufts University -- History
- Arthur W. Leighton, papers, 1913 -- 1973; MS056.001; 1.2 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  The series consists of material relevant to the professional and personal life of Arthur W. Leighton. It contains educational records and correspondence documenting his career at Tufts. It also includes programs, pamphlets, and correspondence pertaining to churches and church organizations with which he was involved, and documents relating to his mother Gertrude W. Leighton.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged chronologically.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Assorted personal papers, 1913 -- 1967; MS056.001.001.00019 (Box Shared 133)
  - Educational Records and Alumni, Tufts Material, Miscellaneous, 1914 -- 1948; MS056.001.001.00020 (Box Shared 133)
    Original file title
  - Leighton, Arthur W., biographical, 1919 -- 1973; MS056.001.001.00021 (Box Shared 133)
  - Church membership and information, 1932 -- 1967; MS056.001.001.00022 (Box Shared 133)
  - North Street Church, 1937 -- 1967; MS056.001.001.00023 (Box Shared 133)
  - Publications: Emerson's "Divinity School Address" and Society of Mayflower Decendents "Forefather's Day", 1938 -- 1951; MS056.001.001.00024 (Box Shared 133)
  - University of Massachusetts reunions, 1941 -- 1967; MS056.001.001.00025 (Box Shared 133)
  - Boston Congregational Club, 1943 -- 1964; MS056.001.001.00026 (Box Shared 133)
  - Woburn Association of Congregational Christian churches, 1947 -- 1949; MS056.001.001.00027 (Box Shared 133)
  - Gertrude W. Leighton, 1949 -- 1955; MS056.001.001.00028 (Box Shared 133)
  - Photos, 1950 -- 1955; MS056.001.001.00029 (Box Shared 133)
  - Board of Ministerial Aid, 1952 -- 1967; MS056.001.001.00030 (Box Shared 133)
  - United Church of Christ, 1960; MS056.001.001.00031 (Box Shared 133)